## Woobin Im

Ph.D. candidate SGVR Lab @ KAIST

Research interest: computer vision, optical flow estimation



2018-current

### About Me

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at KAIST, South Korea. My research is focused on solving **computer vision** problems using **machine learning**. I am especially interested in **motion understanding**, so I have been working on video-related topics.

How to deal with the lack of labeled datasets is where I have expertise. I have mainly studied optical flow estimation with deep learning in an **unsupervised** or **semi-supervised** manner. Recently, I presented two optical flow papers (UnsupSimFlow and FlowSupervisor) at top-tier vision conferences; the two papers are related to unsupervised learning and semi-supervised learning, which are crucial in optical flow learning. I want to research similar topics related to motion understanding and label-efficient learning in the future.

Not only on the topics mentioned above, I'm knowledgeable about general computer vision tasks and robotics. I have implemented my code using Python, C++ with OpenCV, Tensorflow (1 and 2), and Pytorch while participating in many vision-related projects: face recognition, 3D teleportation, and multi-view line matching.

#### Award

- Naver Ph.D Fellowship Award, 2022.
- Finalist at Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea (QIFK), 2020.

#### Education

• KAIST, Ph.D., Computer Science

Advisor: Professor Sung-Eui Yoon

KAIST, M.S., Computer Science
Advisor: Professor Hyun Seung Yang

• Yonsei University, B.S., Computer Science 2012-2016

#### **Publications**

• Semi-Supervised Learning of Optical Flow by Flow Supervisor Woobin Im, Sebin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022 [web] [arxiv] [github]

• In-N-Out: Towards Good Initialization for Inpainting and Outpainting Changho Jo, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon *British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC)*, 2021 [web] [arxiv] [github]

#### • Self-Supervised Visual Odometry via Frame Interpolation

Sebin Lee, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2021 [paper]

#### • Unsupervised Learning of Optical Flow with Deep Feature Similarity

**Woobin Im**, Tae-Kyun Kim, and Sung-Eui Yoon *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2020 [web] [paper] [github]

#### • Combined Center Dispersion Loss Function for Deep Facial Expression Recognition

Abhilasha Nanda, **Woobin Im**, Key-Sun Choi, and Hyun Seung Yang *Pattern Recognition Letters*, 2020 [paper]

#### • Two-stream Spatiotemporal Feature for Video QA Task

Chiwan Song, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05006*, 2019 [arxiv]

#### Acoustic Material Estimation with Convolutional Neural Network

Doheon Lee, Inkyu An, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2019 [paper]

#### An Application of Convolutional-LSTM Network and Video QA

Chiwan Song, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *Korea Computer Congress (KCC)*, 2018 [paper]

#### • Scale-Varying Triplet Ranking with Classification Loss for Facial Age Estimation

**Woobin Im**, Sungeun Hong, Sung-Eui Yoon, and Hyun S. Yang *Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV)*, 2018 [web] [paper] [github]

## • CBVMR: Content-Based Video-Music Retrieval Using Soft Intra-Modal Structure Constraint

Sungeun Hong, **Woobin Im**, and Hyun S. Yang *Proceedings of the ACM international conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR)*, 2018 [paper] [video]

# • D3: Recognizing dynamic scenes with deep dual descriptor based on key frames and key segments

Sungeun Hong, Jongbin Ryu, **Woobin Im**, and Hyun S. Yang *Neurocomputing*, 2018 [paper]

## • SSPP-DAN: Deep Domain Adaptation Network for Face Recognition with Single Sample Per Person

Sungeun Hong, **Woobin Im**, Jongbin Ryu, and Hyun S. Yang *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP'17), IEEE*, 2017 **Oral** [paper]

#### • Convolutional Texture Networks based on Histogram Pooling

Jongbin Ryu, Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, and Hyun S. Yang

• Image-text multi-modal representation learning by adversarial backpropagation Gwangbeen Park and Woobin Im arXiv preprint arXiv:1612.08354, 2016

• Deep CNN-based Person Identification using Facial and Clothing Features Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, Junwoo Park, and Hyun S. Yang *Jun 2016, Summer General Conference '16, IEEK*, 2016

#### **Patents**

- Using Triplet-based Loss for Training Ordinal Classification Deep Models [detail]
- Partial Face Based Person Identification Across Poses [detail]

### **Projects**

- Rendering for teleportaion in AR devices
  - Mar 2018 Dec 2020, funded by National Research Foundation (NRF)
- Lab website renovation, Dec 2019 (sgvr.kaist.ac.kr)
- Age, gender, and expression recognition using face images
  - Dec 2016 Feb 2018, funded by Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology
- Multi-view Face Recognition based on Deep Learning
  - May 2016 May 2017, funded by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)

### Experiences

- Teaching Assistants
  - GSAG-KAIST Research and Education Program, 1/2019-2/2019
  - o CS206: Data Structure (Spring 2019), 3/2019-6/2019
  - o CS688: Web-Scale Image Retrieval (Fall 2018), 9/2018-12/2018
  - CS101: Introduction to Programming, 9/2016-12/2017, 9/2018-12/2018
- Undergraduate Research Assistant
  - o DB Lab, Yonsei University, 1/2014-2/2014